#quiz data for transcription quiz
quiz_data = [
    {
        "question": "What separates DNA strands?",
        "choices": ["DNA Helicase", "RNA Polymerase", "Catalyase"], #will appear on option buttons
        "answer": "RNA Polymerase" # correct answer
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of bonds get broken between complementary base pairs?",
        "choices": ["Phosphodiestaer Bonds", "Ester Bonds", "Hydrogen Bonds"],
        "answer": "Hydrogen Bonds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The template is called the ____ strand.",
        "choices": ["antisense", "sense", "Antiparallel"],
        "answer": "antisense"
    },
    {
        "question": "Free nucleotides line up by complementary base pairing and adjacent nucleotides are joined by ____ bonds",
        "choices": ["sulphuric", "phosphodiester", "ester"],
        "answer": "phosphodiester"
    },
    {
        "question": "What molecule is made?",
        "choices": ["DNA", "tRNA", "mRNA"],
        "answer": "mRNA"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does it leave to attach to the ribosomes",
        "choices": ["nuclear pore", "channel protien", "diffusion"],
        "answer": "nuclear pore"
    }
]

quiz_data1 = [
    {
        "question": "What bonds keep amino acids together?",
        "choices": ["Hydrogen", "Peptide", "Ester"],
        "answer": "Peptide"
    },
    {
        "question": "tRNA binds to specific amino acids from the cytoplasm depending on its ____.",
        "choices": ["template strand", "codon", "anticodon"],
        "answer": "anticodon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the 't'in tRNA",
        "choices": ["transfer", "triple", "teletubbies"],
        "answer": "transfer"
    },
    {
        "question": "Free nucleotides line up by complementary base pairing and adjacent nucleotides are joined by ____ bonds",
        "choices": ["sulphuric", "phosphodiester", "ester"],
        "answer": "phosphodiester"
    },
    {
        "question": "____ anticodons of tRNA bind to mRNA codons and are held in place by hydrogen bonds.",
        "choices": ["Opposite", "Complementary", "Random"],
        "answer": "Complementary"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ribosome joins the amino acids aached to two tRNA molecules by a pepde bond and then tRNA molecules detach from the amino acids. This process is repeated until ____",
        "choices": ["chain gets too long", "amino acids run out", "stop codon is reached"],
        "answer": "stop codon is reached"
      
    },
    {
      "question": "If the DNA code reads CCAATTGG then the tRNA code would read ____",
      "choices": ["GGTTAACC", "GGUUAACC", "CCTTAAGG"],
      "answer": "GGTTAACC"

    }
]
